<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Content and Tooling – puppetlabs-iis</title><link>https://puppetlabs.github.io/content-and-tooling-team/blog_tags/puppetlabs-iis/</link><description>Recent content in puppetlabs-iis on Content and Tooling</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://puppetlabs.github.io/content-and-tooling-team/blog_tags/puppetlabs-iis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: 2021-05-07: IAC &amp; DevX Team Status Update</title><link>https://puppetlabs.github.io/content-and-tooling-team/blog/updates/2021-05-07-status-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://puppetlabs.github.io/content-and-tooling-team/blog/updates/2021-05-07-status-update/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="community-day">Community Day&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This week it was a bank holiday in EMEA, therefore community day has been rescheduled for next Monday.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="content-support-team">Content Support team&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As already mentioned this week, it was been pretty quiet with most of us on holidays. However we did manage to get a &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/puppetlabs-iis/pull/321">customer issue on our puppetlabs-iis module&lt;/a> addressed. The team was made aware of this on Tuesday, it was picked up and triaged on Wednesday, reviewed and merged on Thursday and we aim for release on Monday during our team triage day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re currently overhauling our Contribution Guidelines to reflect the new processes we introduced in the last year in &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/iac/pull/242">this PR&lt;/a>.
Have a look and tell us what you think!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="developer-experience">Developer Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Work continues on reducing package size and improving templates. We presented some early concepts to a few customers in a TAB session to gain feedback on our direction and implementation. We received some great feedback from this session that will help us get the tooling available sooner for more feedback from a wider audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cloud-ci">Cloud CI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This week we have put together the multi-node walkthrough blog post available &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/iac/pull/237/files">here&lt;/a> and finished the demo for porting modules to Cloud CI. This work will be very useful in the near future as other teams are starting to look into the possibilities offered by the Cloud CI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have also started work on the investigations needed to support the possibility of provisioning developer environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- check https://tickets.puppetlabs.com/secure/RapidBoard.jspa?rapidView=1176&amp;quickFilter=8745 for other tickets closed out this week that should be mentioned here --></description></item></channel></rss>